<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="184" moduleid="7389" modulename="book" contextid="29059">
  <book id="184">
    <name>Contextualized Learning and Integrated Learning Objectives </name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_Toc492977176"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Contextualized Learning and Integrated Learning Objectives &lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1505270585</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511985435</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1273">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Strategies for integrating Workforce Preparation Activities and employability skills</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;As we’ve discussed, workforce preparation and employability skills are skills that can be taught through any class topic or content, if the learning objectives explicitly include workforce preparation skills and awareness of their general transferability to varied contexts. Further, intentional implementation of instructional methods and approaches that promote deeper learning can foster workforce preparation and employability skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the ability to apply academic knowledge and problem-solving skills to a variety of contexts and situations is at the core of deeper learning and knowledge transfer, and is one of the three pillars of the Employability Skills Framework. Further, WIOA requires adult educators to address students’ employment and career goals more directly than we might have previously. This is affirmed by the new outcomes measures related to employment and wages (discussed in Course #1) and the inclusion of workforce preparation activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final topic of this course, then, will look at strategies and examples for integrating workforce preparation and employability skills into lessons that are explicitly contextualized to a variety of real-life settings and contexts related to career exploration, careers in specific industry or occupational sectors, and daily life. These strategies can be used to help students see how the skills they are learning can apply directly to situations and problems they might encounter in their current workplaces or if they are to pursue education and training along a specific career pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a deeper exploration of contextualized instruction, the Adult Career Pathways online learning series offers an entire course on &lt;a href="https://auth.lincs.ed.gov/idp/Authn/UserPassword"&gt;Designing Contextualized Instruction&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/33603695_m.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Photo of adult students in a classroom" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1505270693</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1274">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Why contextualize instruction?</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Contextualized instruction involves a variety of instructional strategies, typically using authentic materials, to teach foundational academic skills applied to a variety of contexts, i.e. situations encountered outside of the classroom, such as the workplace, community, or family life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skills and concepts are learned more effectively in a context which highlights the relevance to real-world situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deeper learning is promoted when the brain can attach new concepts and information to familiar concepts and prior knowledge (such as might be provided in instruction contextualized to a familiar situation one might encounter in daily life, whether at work, home, or community).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a contextualized classroom, students discover meaningful relationships between abstract ideas and practical applications in the context of the real world; concepts are internalized through the process of discovering, reinforcing, and relating.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn1"&gt;[30]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Now let's revisit an example of a contextualized lesson, &lt;a href="https://lincs-ovae-moodle-dev.civicactions.net/pluginfile.php/4230/mod_resource/content/10/General%20Education%20Lesson_Fitness.pdf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Create a Brochure for a Fitness Program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Continue on to the &lt;em&gt;Integrating Learning Objectives Lesson&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref1"&gt;[30]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Center for Occupational Research and Development &lt;a href="http://www.cord.org/cord_ctl_overview.php"&gt;http://www.cord.org/cord_ctl_overview.php&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1528379585</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>