<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="187" moduleid="7393" modulename="book" contextid="29063">
  <book id="187">
    <name>Developing Contextualized Lessons</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Developing Contextualized Lessons&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1505271835</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511985483</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1284">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Existing contextualized curriculum resources</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;There are many existing contextualized curriculum resources that you can use and modify for your purposes. You can also build contextualized lessons around authentic materials that you gather to illustrate how skills are applied to different settings and to expose students to the types of materials, ways of thinking, and problems encountered in a variety of workplace and other settings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="333" alt="Photo of laptop, books, magazines, CD-ROM" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/18019017_m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1505321921</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1285">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Authentic materials when using contextualized lessons </title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;When teachers use bus schedules to teach English Language Learners how to navigate transit systems and timetables, they are using authentic materials to teach concepts and skills. When a transition to college program practices critical reading strategies using articles about early childhood education drawing from scholarly, trade, and popular publications, they are learning reading strategies and also learning about the field of early childhood education, using authentic materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, you might use authentic materials from a workplace, such as employee handbooks, occupational training manuals, work order forms and accident reports to teach academic concepts and skills as they are used in a workplace setting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/48227051_m.jpg" width="500" height="334" alt="Photo of someone filling out an application for employment " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1505271986</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1286">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Authentic materials when using contextualized lessons </title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Seek out community members you can interview and observe at work or engaged in an activity or hobby where they use the skills in context. Then ask for their help to construct realistic and relatable classroom and lesson scenarios. They can also help you identify authentic materials that would be used in a specific activity or workplace. Your students can also share examples of situations they encounter from their own workplaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several sources that host authentic materials and information you can use to construct lessons and scenarios contextualized to the workplace or real-world scenarios. Using authentic workplace materials shows students how academic and workforce preparation skills are applied in a workplace setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore the following sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;America’s Job Centers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Career and Technical Education faculty (secondary and postsecondary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional and trade industry associations and publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O*NET Online and other career exploration websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube and other open resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business section of the newspaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help wanted ads and websites &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/12556656_m.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Photo of construction workers looking at blueprints and documents on a clipboard" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1505916360</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1287">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Resources for career- related contextualized lessons</title>
        <content>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;We’ll return now to the list of workforce preparation activities and identify some resources you can use to build lessons that integrate academic skill building workforce preparation/employability skills, taught explicitly in the context of exploring careers and the types of problems and applied skills used in the workplace, generally, and in specific occupations. Selected resources are shown below, but please note that this is not an exhaustive list. You may wish to print this page using the print icon in the upper right hand corner of the Moodle platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources for Teaching Workforce Preparation and Employability Skills &lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;ABE /ESL Curriculum &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contextualized to General WorkForce Preparation and Employability Skills &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Default"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Courses to Employment (C2E)&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aspenwsi.org/resource/c2e-curricula/"&gt;http://www.aspenwsi.org/resource/c2e-curricula/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Default"&gt;Collection of curriculum and lesson plans used in C2E career pathways projects that can be used by instructors and navigators. Partnership tools &lt;a href="http://www.aspenwsi.org/resource/c2e-partnership-tools/"&gt;http://www.aspenwsi.org/resource/c2e-partnership-tools/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Integrating Career Awareness into the ABE &amp;amp; ESOL Classroom curriculum guide (ICA) &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://collegetransition.org/docs/ICAcurriculumguide.pdf"&gt;http://collegetransition.org/docs/ICAcurriculumguide.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The&lt;em&gt; Integrating Career Awareness into the ABE &amp;amp; ESOL Classroom &lt;/em&gt;curriculum is a ready-to-use, flexible curriculum that prepares adult educators to incorporate career awareness and planning into their instructional and counseling activities. The lessons and handouts can be adapted for a range of students and skill levels. Read the &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-246"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;ICA &lt;/em&gt;curriculum in the &lt;em&gt;LINCS&lt;/em&gt; Resource Collection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESOL instructors from Nevada modified a number of the ICA lessons for low and intermediate English Language Learners. &lt;a href="http://www.nevadaadulteducation.org/Educators/Content_Standards_and_Curricula/Integrating_Career_Awareness_into_the_ABE_and_ESOL_Classroom.html"&gt;http://www.nevadaadulteducation.org/Educators/Content_Standards_and_Curricula/Integrating_Career_Awareness_into_the_ABE_and_ESOL_Classroom.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exploring Work-Based Foundational Skills in the ABLE Classroom&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.paadultedresources.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/foundation_skills_in_able_classroom.pdf"&gt;http://www.paadultedresources.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/foundation_skills_in_able_classroom.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide, developed for PA adult educators, contains activities and resources to help adult learners develop the work-based foundation skills and knowledge, which overlap substantially with the Employability Skills Framework and the workforce preparation activities outlined in WIOA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guide is divided into two main parts: Practitioner Section and Learner Guide. The Practitioner Section contains modules for teaching foundation skills organized into four categories: Basic Employability Skills, Basic Workplace Knowledge, Basic Workplace Skills, and Lifelong Learning Skills. The category of Employability Skills includes Works in Teams, Makes Decisions, Solves Problems, Demonstrates Effective Interpersonal Relations, and Demonstrates Self-Management Strategies. The Learner Guide includes skill self-appraisal tools that can be used to set learning goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;WIOA-Friendly Contextualized Curriculum&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://abspd.appstate.edu/wioa-friendly-contextualized-curriculum"&gt;https://abspd.appstate.edu/wioa-friendly-contextualized-curriculum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is from the Adult Basic Skills Professional Development Project at Appalachian State University in North Carolina. It contains some simple classroom activities and other lesson planning resources that can help instructors meet integrate workforce preparation activities into cross-disciplinary lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Strategies for Successful Students: Facilitator’s Guide&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nelrc.org/publications/index.html"&gt;http://www.nelrc.org/publications/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ready-to-deliver workshop presents five strategies that students can use to improve their memory and academic performance. The strategies are based on evidence from neuroscience about long-term memory; research on self-affirmation and self-efficacy theory; and study habits of successful students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workforce Preparation Skills Lessons from Nevada Adult Education&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nevadaadulteducation.org/Educators/Workforce_Preparation_Skills_Lessons.html"&gt;http://www.nevadaadulteducation.org/Educators/Workforce_Preparation_Skills_Lessons.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection of lessons integrates workforce preparation and job readiness skills into lessons aligned with the CCRS, organized according to educational functioning level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contextualization: Creating Career-Infused Classrooms&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/55a158b4e4b0796a90f7c371/t/56f9e2282fe131b0560666f6/1459217002638/contextinstructor-toolkit.pdf"&gt;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/55a158b4e4b0796a90f7c371/t/56f9e2282fe131b0560666f6/1459217002638/contextinstructor-toolkit.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This toolkit provides tools for infusing lessons with career exploration and information about high demand jobs in your area. Academic skills contextualized with employability (soft) skills, occupational contexts, and career planning lead our students along career pathways ending with jobs with family sustaining incomes.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;ABE /ESL Curriculum Contextualized to Specific Occupations or Career Clusters&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Occupational Prep Curriculum&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.spps.org/site/default.aspx?PageType=3&amp;amp;DomainID=11811&amp;amp;ModuleInstanceID=56630&amp;amp;ViewID=6446EE88-D30C-497E-9316-3F8874B3E108&amp;amp;RenderLoc=0&amp;amp;FlexDataID=35820&amp;amp;PageID=22083" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.spps.org/site/default.aspx?PageType=3&amp;amp;DomainID=11811&amp;amp;ModuleInstanceID=56630&amp;amp;ViewID=6446EE88-D30C-497E-9316-3F8874B3E108&amp;amp;RenderLoc=0&amp;amp;FlexDataID=35820&amp;amp;PageID=22083&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Includes contextualized ABE curriculum for a variety of occupations from Hubbs Center for Adult Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contextualized Bridge Class Curriculum&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.siue.edu/SIPDC/Transitioning/Curriculum.htm"&gt;http://www.siue.edu/SIPDC/Transitioning/Curriculum.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Southern Illinois Professional Development Center developed curriculum and resources in healthcare, manufacturing, and transportation, distribution, and logistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Massachusetts Transformation Agenda Contextualized Curriculum&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://mccwdta.etlo.org/module-list"&gt;http://mccwdta.etlo.org/module-list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literacy and Mathematics lesson modules contextualized to advanced manufacturing, healthcare, and information technology. An account is required, but the modules are free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SkillsCommons&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.skillscommons.org/"&gt;https://www.skillscommons.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkillsCommons is an online repository of materials developed by community colleges working in partnership with adult education programs to create career pathways under the U.S. Department of Labor’s Trade Adjustment Assistance Community College and Career Training (TAACCCT) grant funding. The repository can be searched by resource type and industry. Many of the resources are more appropriate for the community college setting. However, adult educators developing workforce preparation and contextualized lessons may benefit from learning about career pathway programs aligned with workforce and industry and designed to support adult student success. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing English Learners for Work and Career Pathways &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/sites/default/files/LINCS_CLR-1_508_0.pdf"&gt;https://lincs.ed.gov/sites/default/files/LINCS_CLR-1_508_0.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Learning Companion is the practitioner supplement to&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Preparing English Learners for Work and Career Pathways: Issue Brief&lt;/i&gt;. It contains a collection of strategies, tools, lesson ideas, and tasks to support the creation of career-focused, contextualized, English language acquisition (ELA) instruction. There are also numerous links to follow, each an invitation to explore contextualized ELA instruction a little more deeply, helping you prepare your learners for the career pathways that match their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;CUNY Career Kit&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.cuny.edu/academics/academic-programs/model-programs/cuny-college-transition-programs/adult-literacy/cuny-careerkit-for-hse-esl-learners/#1482333395299-73a0a724-c92b"&gt;http://www2.cuny.edu/academics/academic-programs/model-programs/cuny-college-transition-programs/adult-literacy/cuny-careerkit-for-hse-esl-learners/#1482333395299-73a0a724-c92b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.cuny.edu/academics/academic-programs/model-programs/cuny-college-transition-programs/adult-literacy/cuny-careerkit-for-hse-esl-learners/#1482333395299-73a0a724-c92b"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The CUNY CareerKit Project is designed to support a range of literacy programming as it intersects with career exploration, planning and preparation. Each Career Kit focuses on one of 10 occupational sectors or clusters, such as healthcare, technology, community and social services and presents a range of lessons, activities and resources that support the continued acquisition of basic language and literacy skills in the broad context of work. Instructional activities include reading and discussion, writing and revising essays, solving word problems, interpreting graphs and conducting research—all on the topic of work - to support the development of basic literacy skills and improved critical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;College and Career Pathways Institute (CCPI) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.laguardia.edu/ccpi/"&gt;http://www.laguardia.edu/ccpi/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CCPI at LaGuardia Community College offers a research-tested Bridge program where students discover key concepts and practice professional skills focused on a specific career pathway. The Bridge Program uses contextualized instruction, a sector focused approach to developmental instruction, to build basic skills. The College and Career Resources section of the website provides sample lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contextual Teaching and Learning Toolkit from Center for Occupational Research and Development (CORD) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://cordonline.net/CTLtoolkit/how-we-teach.php"&gt;http://cordonline.net/CTLtoolkit/how-we-teach.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources for developing lessons using CORD’s REACT (relating, experiencing, applying, cooperating, transferring) approach to contextualized instruction. Instructors can use the career pathway scenarios provided for each of the 16 career clusters to engage students in applying problem solving skills to real workplace situations. &lt;a href="http://cordonline.net/CTLtoolkit/downloads/Sixteen%20Career%20Pathway%20Scenarios.pdf"&gt;http://cordonline.net/CTLtoolkit/downloads/Sixteen%20Career%20Pathway%20Scenarios.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Women Employed Career Foundations and Bridge Program Curriculum&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://womenemployed.org/pathways-careers-network"&gt;http://womenemployed.org/pathways-careers-network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women Employed provides a full course of daily lesson plans for Career Foundations and for bridge programs in healthcare, early childhood education, and transportation, distribution, and logistics (TDL). Lesson plans are available for high intermediate ABE, low ASE, and high ASE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" color="#693300" size="2"&gt;Once you have reviewed these resources continue to the Session 2 Comprehension Check.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506712765</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>