<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="177" moduleid="7377" modulename="book" contextid="29047">
  <book id="177">
    <name>Workforce Preparation Activities &amp; Diverse Student Goals</name>
    <intro>&lt;h2&gt;Workforce Preparation Activities &amp;amp; Diverse Student Goals&lt;span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; mso-bidi-font-family: 'Times New Roman';"&gt;&lt;!--?xml:namespace prefix = "o" ns = "urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" /--&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1505163802</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1505355925</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1247">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Understanding the goals of your students</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Another concern that arises for instructors when discussing WIOA and workforce preparation activities is that the perceived emphasis on employment and career advancement doesn’t match the goals of every student. That is, students enroll in adult education programs with diverse goals and not all of them are goals related to workforce preparation, employment, or career advancement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="502" alt="A road labeled “learning program” divides at the end into many different goals" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/S2_LearningProgram.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506710498</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1248">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Transferable skills in the 21st century</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;As we discussed in course #1, workforce preparation skills as defined in WIOA are not technical or occupational skills and do not require training focused on a specific job or career; they are general and transferable skills. Workforce preparation activities are concerned with improving and deepening students’ learning, communication, analytical, digital, and organizational/management skills, because these skills are valuable and relevant to achieving any goal in any life role or situation they will encounter in the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; century.&lt;a href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates_agb2.docx#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title=""&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;21st Century Skills&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successfully navigating twenty-first century adult life requires far more than basic academic knowledge and skills. On the personal front, adults need to be able to navigate across multiple life roles and identities (as parent, community member, employee, etc.) to confront complex ethical questions, and to make informed decisions in the face of uncertainty.  On the &lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*7399@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=351" target="_blank"&gt;civic&lt;/a&gt; front, they need to be able to articulate and advocate for their perspectives, to engage in productive dialogue across ideological divides, and to decide among imperfect options. On the professional front, they need to be able to tackle open-ended problems in critical, creative, and collaborative ways and to engage in ongoing learning that allows them to adapt to the needs of a rapidly changing job market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;Two of the resources reviewed in the first course, &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-763" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;Transitions &lt;span&gt;Integration Framework &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-864" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;Guide to ELA Classroom Activities that Promote Life Skills, College, and Career Readines&lt;/span&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;illustrate this point explicitly. Both frameworks include activities for teaching and demonstrating the skills using scenarios from work, education, community, and personal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="512" alt="Graphic icons of 8 twenty-first century skills, including Academic, Critical Thinking, Interpersonal, Resource Management, Information Use, Communication, Systems Thinking and Technology Use" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/WP_2_21stCenturySkills.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt; Heller, R., Wolfe, R., and Steinberg, A. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Rethinking Readiness&lt;/em&gt;. Mehta &amp;amp; Fine, pg. 11&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506700645</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1249">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Transferable skills: Long-term goals vs. short-term goals </title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Another related concern, commonly expressed by teachers, is that students with the goal of obtaining a high school equivalency just want to focus on test preparation, and English Language Learners just want to learn English. In that case, we must ask our students: What do you want to do with your high school equivalency that you can’t do now? What do you want to do with your improved English skills that you can’t do now? Instructors must help students make a connection between their broader, longer-term goals, beyond high school and English skill attainment and the breath, depth, and &lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*7399@$&amp;amp;mode=letter&amp;amp;hook=T&amp;amp;sortkey=&amp;amp;sortorder=asc" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;transferability &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;of the skills we’re teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="333" style="float: left;" alt="List of checkboxes showing short-term, long-term and both.  Both is checked." src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/28109815_m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1505843465</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1250">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Application of Workforce Preparation Activities skills</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;While we are committed to designing instruction that responds to students’ goals and motivations, this doesn’t mean that we should ignore general skills, referred to as “workforce preparation” or “employability” skills, for students whose goals are outside the domain of employment or career advancement. Instead, it is our duty as educators to illustrate how each skill can be applied to other circumstances and help students articulate the relevance and value of each skill to their goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a college preparation activity, a teacher might have students identify the steps in a multi-week research project and use a calendar to reverse plan. The teacher can help all students (and especially those who are not interested in college) identify other situations (projects, goals) where these planning skills could be applied in order to engage them in the relevance of the lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="409" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="Graph of achievement where the x-axis is Skills, the y-axis is Choices and the line shows an increase in achievement as skills and choices increase" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/s2_ChoicesSkills.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506710564</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1251">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Importance of general skills</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;At the same time, not every workforce preparation or employability skill has to be taught in the context of a lesson about the workplace, employment or careers. Because these are &lt;b&gt;general&lt;/b&gt; transferable learning, communication and critical thinking skills, as opposed to occupational or technical skills, they are not content-bound. A lesson might be about any subject or content theme and still be designed to teach and practice workforce and employability skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Example&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the earlier example of reverse planning to manage time and complete a research project in the context of college preparation. Teachers can engage students in brainstorming work situations in which project planning and time management are equally important, to illustrate how these skills transfer to the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="327" alt="Teacher leading a class of adult learners" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/42360177_m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1505843560</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1252">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Multiple learning objectives</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;What’s most important in teaching these transferable skills is that teachers help students recognize the multiple goals and objectives of instruction – the academic content and skills, as well as the general workforce preparation or employability skills - and help students make explicit connections between the skills and their application to the students’ goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help students connect the learning objectives to their goals, teachers can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be transparent and explicit about all the skills being taught/practiced – not just the academic skills. Engage students in brainstorming what skills they are learning and how they can be applied in different contexts.&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="#_ftn1"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present the workforce preparation skills, such as the Employability Skills Framework, as a learning tool in class and explain that these skills will be woven into instruction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage students in brainstorming why these skills are important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce the concept of “&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*7399@$&amp;amp;mode=letter&amp;amp;hook=T&amp;amp;sortkey=&amp;amp;sortorder=" target="_blank"&gt;transferable skills&lt;/a&gt;” and engage students in brainstorming examples of how these skills are relevant to their goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage students in brainstorming scenarios and settings where these skills can be used (and the consequences where these skills are absent).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant the seeds for the practice of self-aware learning and meta-cognition through the process of identifying learning objectives and transferable skills. This sort of self-awareness is a foundation for the skill of self-management and taking responsibility for learning. Similarly, students also gain practice working with the concept of transfer and application, a foundation for deeper learning, which we’ll discuss later in the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Continue to Activity 1: Finding Employability Skills in a Lesson.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="#_ftnref1"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;Vander Ark, T. and Schneider, C. (2013). &lt;i&gt;Deeper Learning: For Every Student Every Day&lt;/i&gt;, Getting Smart, &lt;a href="http://www.gettingsmart.com/publication/deeper-learning-every-student-every-day/" target="_blank" id="LPlnk917927" previewinformation="1"&gt;http://www.gettingsmart.com/publication/deeper-learning-every-student-every-day/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506701960</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>