<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="179" moduleid="7380" modulename="book" contextid="29050">
  <book id="179">
    <name>Activity 2: Find Employability Skills in Your Own Lessons</name>
    <intro>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name="_Toc492977148"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Activity 2: Find Employability Skills in Your Own Lessons&lt;!--?xml:namespace prefix = "o" ns = "urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" /--&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1505234638</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511985316</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1257">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Step 1: Choose and analyze the lesson/unit</title>
        <content>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a lesson or a set of lessons (unit) from your instructional offerings. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the lesson/unit and search for ways that employability skills are already incorporated. Use the &lt;a href="http://cte.ed.gov/employabilityskills/index.php/developingskills/create_checklist" target="_blank"&gt;Employability Skills Framework: Lesson Planning Checklist &lt;/a&gt;as a guide to prompt your search for employability skills learned or practiced via the lesson and classroom activities. Make notes on the checklist about how students practice and demonstrate the targeted employability skill(s) in each lesson. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that a single lesson or unit won’t address all or even most of the skills.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are looking at a series of lessons from a unit, notice whether opportunities are provided for students to practice and demonstrate the skills across multiple lessons, to reinforce the learning.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For self-assessment purposes, it may be helpful to think about a group of lessons to see how employability skills are embedded throughout a unit. Give yourself 1 point for every “yes” in a section. Use the last column (“Description of Activity”) to record notes about how the skills are being taught.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;When you are finished with the steps above, continue to the questionnaire: Step 2: Document your findings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506458195</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>