<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="174" moduleid="7374" modulename="book" contextid="29044">
  <book id="174">
    <name>Course Introduction</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Course Introduction&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1505162642</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1512396404</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1238">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Introduction and learning objectives</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;i&gt;Workforce Preparation Activities in the Classroom: Contextualizing Employability Skills for Deeper Learning&lt;/i&gt;. This course is designed for adult educators, administrators, teachers, and advisors who would like more familiarity with how workforce preparation and employability skills can be incorporated into instructional activities. It is recommended that learners also complete the &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/learning-portal" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Introduction to Workforce Preparation and Employability Skills &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;course, which covers workforce preparation and the specific skills outlined in the U.S. Department of Education’s &lt;a href="http://cte.ed.gov/employabilityskills/"&gt;Employability Skills Framework&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;i&gt;Introduction to&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Workforce Preparation and Employability Skills&lt;/i&gt; course is referred to as course #1 throughout this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing this course, you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the rationale behind contextualized instruction that simultaneously addresses college and career readiness instruction and general workforce preparation and employability skills, and demonstrate how this rationale is already incorporated into an existing curriculum. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain best practices concerning workforce preparation activities as referenced in WIOA and illustrate how these practices are currently being used to teach employability skills to adult learners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locate resources you can use to develop and incorporate workforce preparation activities into curriculum and instruction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please allow approximately 80 minutes to complete this course (more or less 40 minutes for session 1 and 40 minutes for session 2). However, you are free to leave the session at any time. When you exit the courseware, a bookmark is automatically placed at your last location to allow you to pick up where you left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506516598</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1239">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Course overview and goals</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;In course #1, &lt;i&gt;Introduction to Workforce Preparation and Employability Skills&lt;/i&gt;, you learned about the passage of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA), and its’ impact on adult education and literacy providers, namely the requirement to include workforce preparation activities in adult education to prepare them for successful transitions to postsecondary education, training, and employment or advancement in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course, &lt;i&gt;Workforce Preparation Activities in the Classroom: Contextualizing Employability Skills for Deeper Learning&lt;/i&gt;, will further explore the concepts, techniques and resources related to incorporating workforce preparation activities into program design and instructional activities to achieve deeper learning skills. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary goals of this course are twofold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To illustrate how incorporating workforce preparation skills enhances, rather than detracts from, rigorous academic instruction and deeper learning. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To present and practice the concept of contextualizing lessons so workforce preparation activities and employability skills can be fully integrated into the learning objectives, thus resulting in deeper learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1505309384</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1240">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Join the LINCS community and participate in course discussions</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;As with all LINCS courses, this course includes opportunities to connect with other adult educators. If you haven’t already done so, take a moment to explore the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Community &lt;/a&gt;and participate in the discussions embedded throughout this course. The discussions provide an open forum to share your thoughts, ideas, and questions with other adult education practitioners. This is a great opportunity to share and learn from others. We encourage you to participate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="550" height="507" alt="Screen shot of the LINCS community home page." src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Lincs%20community%20screenshot_9-12.JPG" /&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Continue to Workforce Preparation Activities across Resources.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506456054</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1241">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Introduction and learning objectives</title>
        <content>&lt;h2&gt;Terminal Objectives (TOs) and Enabling Objectives (EOs)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;Session 1: Best Practices for Teaching Employability Skills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;TO: &lt;/b&gt;Understand the rationale behind contextualized instruction that simultaneously addresses college and career readiness instruction and general workforce preparation and employability skills, and demonstrate how this rationale is already incorporated into an existing curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;EOs&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;After completing this session, you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc" style="text-align: left;"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-1: Explain the overlap in goals and objectives between college and career readiness instruction and general workforce preparation and employability skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-2: Define and demonstrate transferable skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-3: Describe ways teachers can help students connect learning objectives to their goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;While referring to the Workforce Preparation Activities &amp;amp; Employability Skills checklist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc" style="text-align: left;"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-4: Identify examples of contextualized instructional activities in existing lessons/units that teach employability skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-5: Identify lessons and units you currently teach that would readily support the addition of workforce preparation and employability skills objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-6: Create a contextualized lesson or unit where workforce preparation activities and employability skills are fully integrated into the learning objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;Session 2: Deeper Learning in Workforce Preparation Activities Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;TO&lt;/b&gt;: Understand best practices concerning workforce preparation activities as referenced in WIOA and illustrate how these practices are currently being used to teach employability skills to adult learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;EO&lt;/b&gt;s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;After completing this session, you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;2-1: List the six key practices of deeper learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;2-2: Describe examples of deeper learning practices in the classroom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;2-3: Explain why using lessons contextualized explicitly to real-life settings are the best way to teach adult learners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;2-4: Describe strategies for creating contextualized lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: left;"&gt;2-5: Identify resources that support &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;developing contextualized lessons&lt;/span&gt; that include academic content and workforce preparation and employability skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to continue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506634778</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>