<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="183" moduleid="7388" modulename="book" contextid="29058">
  <book id="183">
    <name>Six Key Practices to Promote Deeper Learning</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Six Key Practices to Promote Deeper Learning&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1505239403</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511985417</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1266">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Six key practices to promote deeper learning</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Prompt" style="text-align: left;"&gt;Workplace Preparation Skills and Competencies (WPSC)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Research Council summarized findings from an extensive study, &lt;i&gt;Education for Life and Work: Developing Transferable Knowledge in the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Century&lt;/i&gt;, into a more accessible, practical &lt;i&gt;Guide for Practitioners&lt;/i&gt; that outlines six practices that promote deeper learning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skills include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage learners in challenging tasks, with supportive guidance and feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach with examples and cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prime student motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use formative assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Click on each workforce preparation skill for more information and resources.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--REPLACE MAIN IMAGE--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="450" height="500" style="margin-right: auto; margin-left: auto; display: block;" alt="Workforce preparation skills and competencies for the classroom graphic which include Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks, use formative assessment, prime student motivation, teach with examples and cases, engage learners in challenging tasks with supportive guidance and feedback, and encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation." src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/S2_SkillsCompetencies_Web%20Ready.png" usemap="#navmap" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--/REPLACE MAIN IMAGE--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;map name="navmap"&gt; 
&lt;area title="Skills necessary for successful transition" href="#" shape="poly" coords="3,277,548,336" target="_top" alt="Skills necessar for successful transition" name="Link to Workforce Preparation Skills and Competencies Graphic" /&gt;
 
&lt;area title="Key Practice 1: Use multiple and varied" href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1267@$" shape="poly" coords="137,22,313,29,264,122,176,128" target="_top" alt="Workforce preparation skills and competencies for the classroom graphic which include Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks, use formative assessment, prime student motivation, teach with examples and cases, engage learners in challenging tasks with supportive guidance and feedback, and encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation." name="Link to Workforce Preparation Skills and Competencies Graphic" /&gt;
 
&lt;area title="Key Practice 6: Use formative assessment" href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1272@$" shape="poly" coords="38,108,144,112,130,178,28,185" target="_top" alt="Workforce preparation skills and competencies for the classroom graphic which include Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks, use formative assessment, prime student motivation, teach with examples and cases, engage learners in challenging tasks with supportive guidance and feedback, and encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation." name="Link to Workforce Preparation Skills and Competencies Graphic" /&gt;
 
&lt;area title="Key Practice 5: Prime student motivation" href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1271@$" shape="poly" coords="18,250,121,255,136,315,49,345" target="_top" alt="Workforce preparation skills and competencies for the classroom graphic which include Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks, use formative assessment, prime student motivation, teach with examples and cases, engage learners in challenging tasks with supportive guidance and feedback, and encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation." name="Link to Workforce Preparation Skills and Competencies Graphic" /&gt;
 
&lt;area title="Key Practice 4: Teach with examples" href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1270@$" shape="poly" coords="172,338,273,336,286,411,160,414" target="_top" alt="Workforce preparation skills and competencies for the classroom graphic which include Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks, use formative assessment, prime student motivation, teach with examples and cases, engage learners in challenging tasks with supportive guidance and feedback, and encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation." name="Link to Workforce Preparation Skills and Competencies Graphic" /&gt;
 
&lt;area title="Key Practice 3: Engage Learners" href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1269@$" shape="poly" coords="319,241,431,250,391,370,294,352" target="_top" alt="Workforce preparation skills and competencies for the classroom graphic which include Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks, use formative assessment, prime student motivation, teach with examples and cases, engage learners in challenging tasks with supportive guidance and feedback, and encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation." name="Link to Workforce Preparation Skills and Competencies Graphic" /&gt;
 
&lt;area title="Key Practice 2: Encourage Elaboration" href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1268@$" shape="poly" coords="297,93,428,96,437,205,304,209" target="_top" alt="Workforce preparation skills and competencies for the classroom graphic which include Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks, use formative assessment, prime student motivation, teach with examples and cases, engage learners in challenging tasks with supportive guidance and feedback, and encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation." name="Link to Workforce Preparation Skills and Competencies Graphic" /&gt;
 &lt;/map&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506460277</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1267">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key Practice 1: Use multiple and varied representations of concepts and tasks </title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;People understand and remember information better when it is presented in varied formats – visual, verbal, auditory – because more varied representations allow the mind to create multiple routes and connections to existing knowledge for retrieving information.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn1"&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an essay called &lt;i&gt;Ambitions Teaching&lt;/i&gt;, the author illustrates this concept in a teacher’s approach to teaching about the rate of change. The teacher poses a word problem using a real-world scenario of a road trip undertaken by two different drivers traveling at different speeds. She hangs five sheets of poster paper on the wall, each depicting the problem with a different coordinate graph or verbal description of the scenario, represented by the graphs. By linking the graphs to the verbal descriptions, she enables the students to connect the abstract concepts represented by the graphs to a familiar experience, a road trip, providing a mental anchor. In addition to the potential to engage the students in solving daily-life problems, the scenarios have a cognitive function. They create mental structures that allow the students to carry the knowledge from one (familiar) situation to a new situation and they will use those structures as they get further into the subsequent lessons and problems. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn2"&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Practices in Action: What it Looks Like in the Classroom&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/keypractices_small_gray2.jpg" width="150" height="127" alt="Magnifying glass over the words Key Practices in Action" style="float: left;" /&gt;Melissa Braaten is a math teacher in Boston. Read below about how she uses multiple and varied representations to teach fractions and division. Her examples come from her work in the GLE 2-5 level classroom (B and C of the CCR Standards) but she suggests that advanced students can also benefit from these strategies to deepen their conceptual understanding. She says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;In general, math lends itself well to multiple representations. We learn abstract mathematical concepts through concrete representations of them. There are some standard visuals – pie charts for fractions, number lines for integers - that are used to teach basic math concepts. But going beyond these typical illustrations and using varied, concrete representations to illustrate single concepts can help students to understand the concept abstractly and grasp how and when it can be applied at a deeper level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, traditionally pie charts, block diagrams, or Singapore value strips might be used to visualize fractions, decimals, and percents. But you also can use rational numbers like fractions. Let’s take a benchmark fraction like ½. Even though we think a half is something people have a lot of intuition about and encounter the concept in everyday life, it’s still quite abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, a geometrical area (a circle) is used to show what half of a whole looks like. I also show ½ represented by groupings. So, for example, I’ll draw 10 stick figures and divide them in half. In this case, a discrete group of figures still represents half of the whole. These are two very distinct representations and ways of thinking about a single concept – half of a whole. This leads us to ask: what does this shape (circle) split into two parts have to do with a group of people now standing on opposite sides of the room? Both the circle and the groups of people represent two equal parts. The parts might pertain to the area of a shape or they might pertain to a quantity (a rational number). But they both represent two equal parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/wholehalfchart.png" width="500" height="214" alt="Table showing four different ways to demonstrate one-half, such as a whole apple and one side of it cut in half, and a dollar and fifty cents" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parts might be area, or they might be a quantity of something, but the key concept to grasp is that they are two parts and they are equal to each other. We tend to think of fractions as geometric shapes, because that’s the most common representation. But it’s important to understand that a half is about more than a shape and can be applied to many contexts. As we get further into abstraction, I introduce probability (50/50) to illustrate the concept of half. There isn’t a typical visual to represent it, but it’s still about halves - one part represents what might happen, the other part represents what won’t happen. And with probability, we often use the number line. Many teachers use the circles with spinning needles (from game boards) to tie the abstract concept to the more familiar and concrete geometric shapes. Each portion of the circle represents the space in which the probability or improbability occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to start with the more concrete and the more varied, but I want to get to a more complex example. If you can start with something more intuitive like a half a circle, and half a group, and see how many different connections there are, then they can build to understanding half in terms of probability. Stretching the ways we represent the concept of half, stretches how students understand the concept and how it presents itself in different contexts. This broader understanding allows students to go further in solving more complex problems in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operation sense can also be approached through multiple representations. So in a unit on division we look at various representations to illustrative the partitive and quotative aspects of division. Partitive signifies the concept of sharing (dividing) the whole up into equal parts. In this case, we might discuss a loan that you have to pay off in 12 months in 12 equal parts. You know what the total is, and you know you need 12 equal parts, but how do you figure out how much each part is? Dealing a deck of cards out to the players in a game is another way to represent the partitive concept. You know how many players are in the game, and how many cards are in the deck, but how do you figure out how many cards each player will end up with? We start with a V diagram and pass out the numbers in three different piles or use manipulatives. We might start with small numbers to share into equal piles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To teach the quotative (subtraction or measurement) aspect of division, I encourage students to think in terms of scoops. For example, how do you divide 24 by 3? You know that you have to scoop out cups of flour from a bag, but you don’t know how many scoops (cups) you’ll end up with. Then we look at how many threes can you scoop out of 24. So then we are scooping cups out of a pitcher of water. Then, I show the same concepts on a number line, how many 4-integer jumps can be taken within the total. If you’re looking at the total running time of a movie, presented in minutes, how do you calculate the number of hours in 60-minute scoops? The same principle is used when converting inches into feet – you measure with 12-inch scoops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are examples of division. The same answer will be derived, but the problem is represented in different ways using concrete examples. The concept is equal groupings – an important concept underlying multiplication and division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the value to studying simple concepts this way? Students often struggle with word problems, although they may be very comfortable with the mechanics of division when given a pair of numbers. But they don’t know how to recognize division in a word problem or as it appears in the real world, so they won’t be able to go beyond the mechanics of the computation. Varied representations help students recognize the problem in multiple contexts, analyze when and how it’s used, and solve it. If you understand that both of these aspects are division, this will help you with procedural fluency/efficiency and you can be more strategic in your approach to solving a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deeper learning activities require learners to draw information from knowledge they have acquired and then do something meaningful with it. Because the brain must develop the internal wiring necessary to process information efficiently in non-routine ways, deeper learning activities should be structured to give students multiple opportunities, over time, to apply knowledge in a range of challenging tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More effective than a typical worksheet or a drill and memorize approach, this approach requires students to use important information repeatedly, in complex and meaningful ways, such as writing papers or completing projects. Further, adding visual representations to text or narration, for example to show how a mechanical or biological system works, can increase knowledge transfer.&lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates_agb2.docx#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1" title=""&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;"&gt;Continue on to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1268@$" style="font-family: verdana; font-size: small;"&gt;Key Practice #2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;"&gt; or return to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYID*7388@$" style="font-family: verdana; font-size: small;"&gt;Six key practices to promote deeper learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;"&gt; to review another key practice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref1"&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Lesgold, M. &amp;amp; Welch-Ross, M. (Eds.). &lt;i&gt;Improving Adult Literacy Instruction: Options for Practice and Research&lt;/i&gt;, National Academies of Science, Pg. 110&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref2"&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;Heller, R., Wolfe, R.E., &amp;amp; Stenberg, A. (Eds.). &lt;i&gt;Rethinking Readiness: Deeper Learning for College, Work, and Life.&lt;/i&gt; Cambridge: Harvard University Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates_agb2.docx#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1" title=""&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Vander Ark, T. and Schneider, C. (2013). &lt;i&gt;Deeper Learning: For Every Student Every Day&lt;/i&gt;, Getting Smart, &lt;a href="http://cdno.gettingsmart.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/DLForEveryStudent_FINAL.pdf"&gt;http://cdno.gettingsmart.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/DLForEveryStudent_FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1512397523</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1268">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key Practice 2: Encourage elaboration, questioning, and self-explanation</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this practice is to “require students to actively engage with the material—going beyond memorizing to process the content in their own words.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn1"&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important aspect of this practice is to create an environment that builds what Lampert refers to as students’ “intellectual courage”. That is, the courage to share their thought processes, ask their questions and justify their answers out loud to the entire class or in pairs and small groups.&lt;a name="_ftnref2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn2"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[11&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;/a&gt; One teacher describes the strategy of elaboration as resisting the impulse to answer a student’s question right away: “We answer a student’s questions with questions, and teachers discipline themselves to ask students ‘why?’ at least three times in order to assess understanding, elicit the critical thinking, problem solving, and effective feedback producing aspects of deeper learning.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn3"&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Practices in Action: What it Looks Like in the Classroom&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/keypractices_small_gray2.jpg" width="150" height="127" alt="Magnifying glass over the words Key Practices in Action" style="float: left;" /&gt;Phil Wormuth is an adult education teacher in Maine who incorporates elaboration and questioning to build critical thinking, reading, and writing skills. He describes his approach this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have built a classroom culture around asking questions starting with establishing norms, expectations, and routine activities where students practice and hone their questioning skills to approach challenging reading texts and build comprehension and knowledge. We have a saying that reflects the culture – “when is it appropriate to ask a question? Anytime; it’s always appropriate to ask a question.” Effective questioning stimulates students to refine their understanding and make accurate/informed inferences. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil’s approach to the Fill the Question Jar activity, an example of how he uses elaboration and questioning in the classroom, is described in his own words below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the beginning of the year, I introduce questioning as a reading strategy. I explain that a good reader (of fiction or non-fiction) continually asks themselves questions to better understand the material and to construct meaning, and introduce three types of questions: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflective questions&lt;/strong&gt;… require people to examine their existing knowledge or information before giving a thoughtful response. Example: “Why did you vote for him in the past election?” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conceptual questions&lt;/strong&gt;… require people to perceive, imagine, predict, hypothesize, and conclude. Example: “Who do you think will win the upcoming presidential election?” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factual questions&lt;/strong&gt;… require people to focus on details and facts rather than interpreting or reacting. Example: “How many candidates are running for president in the upcoming election?” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The question slips I created for the jar are organized in such a way that students must identify which type of question they are asking – reflective, conceptual, or factual. This helps them focus their questions, think about what they are asking and formulate the questions in a way that will elicit the type of information or understanding they’re seeking. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="125" height="188" style="float: left;" alt="Photo of a Question Jar" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/questionjar.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prior to reading, I ask each student to write one question (reflective, conceptual, or factual) about the material we are approaching and put it in the jar. Then each student chooses a question from the jar, which they answer as they read and discuss the text, noting significant facts and details that support and inform their answer. Finally, they share the question they picked and their answer with the group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Initially, I used it as a pre-reading strategy and a reading activity, but now the question jar has become a fixture in my classroom. It’s a flexible, non-threatening way for students to practice asking and answering questions and develop skills in analyzing, inferring, restating, and summarizing. At any point during the class, students can write their questions and use the jar as a sort of parking lot for questions we’ll take up at different points in the lesson (and especially at the end of the lesson). Once all the questions are in the jar, the jar is passed around and everyone has to pick a question to answer and then report out. Sometimes, students use their smart phones to search the answer to factual questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="200" height="200" style="float: right;" alt="Flip Chart showing Webb’s Depth of Knowledge Chart" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/easel.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Depending on the focus/purpose of the lesson, I may ask every student to submit at least one question of a specific type by the end of class.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This year I introduced the Depth of Knowledge chart and we’ve been working on developing questions that move us from level 1 to level 4 types of understanding. First, we looked at the academic language used in the Depth of Knowledge chart and defined the academic terms, and moving from L1 questions to L4 questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phil describes a formative assessment process around asking good questions on the website for the Formative Assessment of Standards Project &lt;a title="http://www.nelrc.org/practice/fast.html" href="http://www.nelrc.org/practice/fast.html"&gt;http://www.nelrc.org/practice/fast.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other examples of elaboration and questioning include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asking open-ended and guiding questions that ask students to articulate their though processes in solving a problem, as well as cite reasons and evidence for their opinions and conclusions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establishing a classroom practice of self-inquiry and elaboration where students are encouraged to question each other.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn4"&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prompting students who are reading a text to explain the material to themselves aloud, in their own words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking learners to summarize what they have learned in writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having students test themselves without external feedback (e.g., by asking themselves questions about material they have just read.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref5" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn5"&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Continue on to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1269@$"&gt;Key Practice #3&lt;/a&gt; or return to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYID*7388@$"&gt;Six key practices to promote deeper learning&lt;/a&gt; to review another key practice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref1"&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;i&gt;Education for Life and Work: Guide for Practitioners&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref2"&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Redefining Readiness pg. 160&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref3"&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Vander Ark, T. and Schneider, C. (2013). Deeper Learning: For Every Student Every Day, Getting Smart, &lt;a href="http://cdno.gettingsmart.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/DLForEveryStudent_FINAL.pdf"&gt;http://cdno.gettingsmart.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/DLForEveryStudent_FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref4"&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn5" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref5"&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;i&gt;Education for Life and Work: Guide for Practitioners, &lt;/i&gt;pg. 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1512397591</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1269">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key Practice 3: Engage learners in challenging tasks, with supportive guidance and feedback</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this practice is to provide opportunities for students to gain mastery, confidence, and self-efficacy in undertaking increasingly complex tasks with guidance and support along the way. Research has shown that without appropriate guidance and feedback along the way, deeper learning doesn’t occur, simply because students are charged with solving a challenging problem. Without the support and guidance, students may end up frustrated and teachers may shy away from challenging tasks and lessons in the future.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn1"&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider creating a culture of high expectations enabled by a high level of support.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn2"&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; High support might include strategies for scaffolding learning of more complex tasks. For example, a teacher might first model an approach to a task or problem, engaging the class in solving it collectively with the teachers’ support, prompting and explanations, then have students work in groups on a related problem or task, with the teacher available to offer advice and feedback, gradually withdrawing instructions and explanations as student gain independence with increasing practice.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn3"&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Instruction of strategies for learning complex materials should be incorporated into the content instruction, to help students approach and master complex and challenging material. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn4"&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Practices in Action: What it Looks Like in the Classroom&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/keypractices_small_gray2.jpg" width="150" height="127" alt="Magnifying glass over the words Key Practices in Action" style="float: left;" /&gt;In his two-part Tech Tips for Teachers blog post, Chris Bouret describes how he prepares his low intermediate level English Language Learners to research a health topic using the internet. Later, students write and record a public service announcement (PSA) on the topic they investigate. For example, before students work with Medline Plus, he has them read some shorter, more basic health articles and review the sorts of vocabulary words they are likely to encounter in their research. He also projects the website onto a large screen and models the navigation features for the entire class, before they begin their own investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img width="500" height="333" alt="Photo of a teacher guiding a student on the computer" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/42311616_m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second post, he describes how he prepares students for developing their PSAs first, using scaffolding techniques such as paragraph frames to guide their writing and leading the class through a collective process of writing a sample PSA together. Finally, before they go on to write their own, they evaluate the PSA example using a rubric that Chris provides, to further break down the elements they are aiming for in their final product. &lt;a href="http://techtipsforteachers.weebly.com/blog/online-health-research-as-a-scaffolded-learning-activity" target="_blank"&gt;Read more about his approach here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the PIAAC Literacy Framework to Guide Instruction: An Introduction for Adult Educators outlines factors to consider in assessing task difficulty to help practitioners plan instruction and adjust reading activities to provide appropriate challenge for students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Continue to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1270@$"&gt;Key Practice #4&lt;/a&gt; or return to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYID*7388@$"&gt;Six key practices to promote deeper learning&lt;/a&gt; to review another key practice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref1"&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref2"&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This is the title of a report on the Community College Survey of Student Engagement, 2008. pg. 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref3"&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref4"&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Lesgold, M. &amp;amp; Welch-Ross, M. (Eds.). Improving Adult Literacy Instruction: Options for Practice and Research. National Academies of Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1512397709</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1270">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key Practice 4: Teach with examples and cases</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this practice is to demonstrate how a concept, principle, or method, can be relevant and applicable to different problems and situations. When using examples and cases, a teacher might first model an approach to the problem or task, as in the previous example of scaffolding, or engage the entire class in working through a case example before they tackle one individually or in small groups.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn1"&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples and cases can also be used to contextualize problem solving to a variety of situations and scenarios. For example, instructors might present a math concept such as finding area, using problems as they are encountered in different occupations, such as construction or web-design. And again, this strategy is not just helpful to engage students in real-world examples of how abstract concepts can be applied; contextualized learning can also provide a structure or mental anchor for retaining and transferring knowledge, because people learn best when engaged in learning that they feel is relevant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/anchor_casestudies.png" width="500" height="396" alt="Image of case studies entering the brain through the eyes and creating a mental anchor there." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like contextualized instruction, case studies provide students with opportunities for considering how information, concepts, and problem-solving skills can be applied to real life settings. In the process, case studies help student develop skills such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asking probing questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifying problems and conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understanding and interpreting data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thinking analytically and critically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making judgments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;communicating, ideas, opinions, solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asking questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifying how solutions can be applied to a variety of situations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the course objectives, teachers might take a &lt;a href="http://www.bu.edu/ctl/teaching-resources/using-case-studies-to-teach/"&gt;systematic approach&lt;/a&gt; to the analysis, asking students to discuss questions like these in sequence:&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the issue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the goal of the analysis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the context of the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What key facts should be considered?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What alternatives are available to the decision-maker?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would you recommend — and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some teachers and advisors use simple scenarios dealing with day to day issues that adult students might encounter.  Scenarios can focus on different personal themes that may interfere with studying, or questions about navigating the college application process. Each group can brainstorm solutions to share with the larger group, following discussion prompts like the questions above. To make the scenario even more interactive, small groups can also role-play the scenarios and have their audience offer suggestions to resolve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Practices in Action: What it Looks Like in the Classroom&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/keypractices_small_gray.jpg" width="150" height="124" alt="Magnifying glass over the words Key Practices in Action" style="float: left;" /&gt;Cynthia Peters teaches GED and ESOL and is the editor of &lt;em&gt;The Change Agent&lt;/em&gt;, a biannual magazine for adult educators and learners. Below, she describes how she uses lesson packets - collections of &lt;em&gt;Change Agent&lt;/em&gt; articles centered on common topics, workplace safety and the work of a Certified Nursing Assistant (CNA) as cases to spark student research, analysis, and presentation skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workplace Safety Case Studies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “&lt;a href="http://175bjf45zi9z2x8vtg1uxr7j.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Packet-4-safety-on-job.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Workplace Safety -- Learn It and Teach It&lt;/a&gt;” lesson packet from &lt;em&gt;The Change Agent&lt;/em&gt; supports students to research a relevant topic and then create a presentation about it to share with fellow students. She says: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Central to the packet are two articles that I treat as case studies. The first article is called “I Got Sick from my Job.” It is by a hotel worker who had an allergic reaction to the strong chemicals she used in the workplace. She wonders if her allergies are related to poverty and poor nutrition growing up. Today, she treats her allergies by trying to strengthen her immune system. The second article is the story of how Boston Public School custodians organized to use green cleaning products instead of cleansers with hazardous ingredients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When I taught this lesson in my workplace-based ESOL class at a downtown hotel, I found the pairing of these two stories to have a powerful effect. The story about the individual struggle with allergies was something everyone could relate to. All the workers at this hotel had experienced some kind of physical irritation due to strong chemicals on the job. And they all had individual remedies and strategies for protecting themselves, though some were resigned to the ill effects. Reading this first article was a powerful way to start thinking about workplace safety because it got everyone talking. We generated vocabulary for the hazards they face and the protections they use. Students were passionate and full of advice and cautions for each other. This particular hotel uses some green cleaning products in some situations, and we examined those. We considered employee habits and employer policies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/casestudies2.jpg" width="250" height="187" alt="Stack of case study articles" style="float: right;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The second article was also about harsh chemicals, but it had a completely different approach. In this one, the story is about how a whole group of custodians fought for a change in the cleaning products they use. And they won. In this story, the perspective is not that of an individual, but of a whole bunch of individuals organized into a group. This changed the conversation in class completely. Now, instead of talking about the benefits of wearing a mask and which allergy meds work better, we were talking about system-wide solutions that can be generated when people mobilize together to make a change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This helped launch a discussion about who is responsible for workplace safety. Is it the worker or the employer or the manufacturer of the cleaning chemicals? Or does the government play a role? Or is it a combination of all of these? Who makes and enforces safety standards? What data must the manufacturer reveal about the ingredients in its products? The case studies had primed their questions and their thinking about how workplace health and safety plays out on a micro as well as macro level. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students further investigated the questions raised by the case discussions and prepared a presentation using Google slides. They worked in pairs to research and present different aspects of the slideshow: 1) What rights, guaranteed by law, do workers have to safety on the job? 2) What is OSHA and how does it work? 3) What are some strategies for reading hard documents, such as Material Safety Data Sheets (MSDS)? 4) What are some ways we stay safe on the job?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creating and then presenting the slide show was a powerful learning experience. By compiling their knowledge and presenting it to others, they solidified their learning and used their English in a public-speaking setting, which boosted their confidence and sense of self-efficacy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not only did students practice using technology (document-sharing software, presentation software, the Internet for searching for information and images, etc.), they also experienced themselves as experts in this area, and they had the chance to hone their presentation skills. They knew their rights, understood OSHA protections, had tried out strategies for reading hard documents, and mined their own deep experience with workplace hazards and protections.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Certified Nursing Assistant Case Studies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In “&lt;a href="http://175bjf45zi9z2x8vtg1uxr7j.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Packet-3-CNA-exploration.pdf"&gt;Thinking about Becoming a CNA&lt;/a&gt;,” I wanted to give students a variety of perspectives about this work, using a series of articles gleaned from &lt;/em&gt;The Change Agent&lt;em&gt; as case studies. In one case, the author shares the joy she feels in taking care of people. Another talks about a dispute she had with her supervisor and the role the union played in helping to resolve the dispute. The third writer discusses how technology improves patient care and facilitates her work as a CNA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These case studies give students a chance to analyze one particular job from multiple perspectives, and they inspire students to think about work from various angles. I ask students, “According to these case studies, what are some of the key skills a CNA should have to do her job well?” The first and third cases provide fairly straightforward answers -- namely, a CNA should enjoy taking care of people and a CNA should be comfortable with how technology is deployed on the job. Then, students consider whether they are drawn to this type of work and have the skills, interests, and personality traits required. The second case -- about standing up for your rights on the job -- requires more critical thinking. Students might have to stretch to think about how they would respond in a similar situation and consider how worker rights and self-advocacy benefit the worker, the workplace, and the patients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Continue to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1271@$"&gt;Key Practice #5&lt;/a&gt; or return to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYID*7388@$"&gt;Six key practices to promote deeper learning&lt;/a&gt; to review another key practice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref1"&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Ibid. pg.10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1512397809</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1271">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key Practice 5: Prime student motivation</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this practice is to tap into and enhance students’ motivation so that they feel that what they are learning is worth the effort and expense it requires of them and they have a sense of their progress towards their goals. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn1"&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that students learn more deeply when they develop positive attitudes and beliefs about themselves in relation to academic work. Students with strong academic mindsets and belief in their ability to learn and progress are more likely to persist through challenges. In turn, as they persist and make progress, their self-efficacy and growth mindset are fortified further.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn2"&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;Additionally, research indicates that student persistence is tied to motivation and connecting learning to one’s goals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cultivate a growth mindset and prime student motivation&lt;a name="_ftnref3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn3"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[22]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help students identify the ways that the knowledge and skills they are learning are relevant to and will help them attain their specific education, career, life goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach students that the brain is like a muscle: the more you exercise the stronger it becomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have explicit conversations with students about ability as an incremental trait that they can affect rather than a fixed trait that you either have or don’t have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have students read about or interview role models who’ve had to work hard to be successful. The message we want to send is that most people become good at what they’re doing through lots of hard work and practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help students recognize their own efforts and steps they take to make progress. In addition to cultivating a growth mindset, it can help students articulate their own learning process, gaining &lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*7399@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=114"&gt;meta-cognitive&lt;/a&gt; awareness and skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="250" height="203" style="float: right;" alt="Graph showing that hard work and persistence lead to a growth mindset" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/growthmindset.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to research&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn4"&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the type of feedback and praise that teachers give students can serve to reinforce or undermine a growth mindset. General praise (“good job”) or praise that highlights intelligence (“you’re smart; you can do this”) instead of effort (“you worked hard at this and made progress”) reinforces the misconception that innate intelligence is the central determinant of academic progress. Students who feel they lack intelligence lose motivation more readily, whereas students who recognize the effort involved in their progress and are given specific praise for their effort and concrete feedback on their progress will more readily maintain motivation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Practices in Action: What it Looks Like in the Classroom&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="150" height="124" style="float: left;" alt="Magnifying glass over the words Key Practices in Action" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/keypractices_small_gray.jpg" /&gt;Patricia, a teacher at Project Hope in Boston tested this theory by intentionally changing the nature of the feedback she gave to her &lt;a href="https://www.startoolkit.org/"&gt;STAR&lt;/a&gt; reading students, and the results she encountered. Below, she describes how she cultivated a growth mind set in her Pre-GED STAR reading class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was studying the concept of growth mindset and the recommended practice of praising effort, rather than intelligence, to foster student motivation. I decided to test whether students’ noticed the difference between what I’d call “empty praise” and specific feedback.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During a 30 minute STAR reading group, I decided to count how many times I used "canned praise phrases", such as “good job”, “nice work”, and noticed six instances. A couple of the students gave me a high-five in response, and a few others managed a little smile, but other than that, the praise didn't seem to make a tremendous impression. For the next nine STAR sessions, I practiced giving more intentional feedback focused on student effort and strengths of the work. For example: "Maneisha, you are putting so much more expression into your reading now." Immediately, Maneisha's chest puffed up and her smile lit up the room. I was amazed! Seriously, I thought, can this really make that much of a difference? So, I tried it again with a different student. "Shaundra, have you noticed how you are paying more attention to pausing at commas?" Well, not only did I get a "Wow. Thanks Trish" from Shaundra, but other students in the group affirmed that they noticed this improvement too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img width="300" height="197" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="Clipboard showing phrases for creating Intentional Feedback which include: &amp;quot;You worked hard at...&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Look at the progress you made on...&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;I like how you've been...&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Have you noticed how you...&amp;quot;. " src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Intentionalfeedback.png" /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was all still feeling a bit awkward for me, and a few times I had to add one of my familiar praise phrases, like "you go girl" to the end of my feedback. What really converted me to this approach is that after a couple of weeks the students themselves started giving each other more focused feedback as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What worked best about this strategy was the positive impact it had on students' self-efficacy. Because their own confidence grew they were able to look outside of themselves enough to recognize the growth in their classmates. It is important to note that the role-modeling and consistent use of this strategy were key in its positive impact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After three weeks, I decided to stop using this strategy to see if the students would notice. I was hoping they would continue to use it with each other. Unfortunately, they stopped too and they didn't even notice or acknowledge that we had stopped. This was disappointing but reinforced the need for consistent ongoing practice for students to really internalize something new.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Continue on to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYIDCH*7388*1272@$"&gt;Key Practice #6&lt;/a&gt; or return to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYID*7388@$"&gt;Six key practices to promote deeper learning&lt;/a&gt; to review another key practice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref1"&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Ibid. pg. 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref2"&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Vander Ark, T. and Schneider, C. (2013). Deeper Learning: For Every Student Every Day, Getting Smart, &lt;a href="http://www.gettingsmart.com/publication/deeper-learning-every-student-every-day/" target="_blank"&gt;http://cdno.gettingsmart.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/DLForEveryStudent_FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref3"&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Andy Nash, presentation to Pennsylvania ABLE case managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref4"&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Dweck, Carol, S. “The Perils and Promises of Praise.”  &lt;i&gt;Educational Leadership.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1536342637</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1272">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key Practice 6: Use formative assessment</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Formative assessment is an assessment &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; learning and the process used to inform both the student and the teacher about the progress the student is making along the path of learning (rather than at the end of the path). Formative assessment is used to inform the teacher of any adjustments that might be required for instruction to be more effective in meeting the students’ needs. Rather than a one-time event, it is an ongoing process for the purpose of guiding the instruction and the learning. Formative assessment is different from summative assessment, which is an assessment &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; learning that typically takes place at the &lt;i&gt;end&lt;/i&gt; (sum) of a process (e.g. curriculum unit, semester/cycle). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The connection of formative assessment to deeper learning, however, is not simply about the timing of the assessment. It is also about the nature and type of assessment and the feedback provided through the process. Research indicates that while practice is essential for deeper learning and skill development, practice without the benefit of quality feedback does not yield substantial learning.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn1"&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaches to formative assessment that promote deeper learning include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design formative assessment processes that: makes learning goals clear to students; entails continual monitoring, feedback and response to students’ progress; and involves students in peer- and self-assessment.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn2"&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a culture and expectation of revision and mastery. Help students value feedback and use it to continually revise and improve their work so they learn the practice of persistence and effort.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn3"&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate formative assessment as a collaboration between the teacher and the students to identify learning goals, outcomes, and criteria for achieving them. Together, identify where the gaps are. This process can increase a students’ self-reflection, self-management and meta cognition skills as well. Student involvement in self-assessment and the understanding they gain about their learning and how to improve it have a profound influence on student motivation and self-esteem.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftnref4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn4"&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide students with a rubric so they know what they are aiming for and can collaborate in an assessment of their own work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give students feedback that is both timely and constructive and have a specific focus. While a piece of writing may need a great deal of revision, teachers should focus on a few issues at once, rather than overload students with critical feedback. For example, perhaps feedback on overall structure of an essay as it related to the content in one session. In a follow-up session, the teacher can look at grammar and punctuation.&lt;a name="_ftnref5" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn5"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[28]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To cultivate a growth mindset, give students concrete, specific feedback on their academic performance rather than general praise. Help students learn to attribute low performance or struggle to things that are within their control, such as effort or showing up rather than lack of ability.&lt;a name="_ftnref6" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftn6"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[29]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Acknowledge and praise their efforts through prompts such as:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;You really studied for your English test, and your improvement shows it. You read the material several times, outlined it, and tested yourself on it. That really worked!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;I like the way you tried all kinds of strategies on that math problem.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;It was a long, hard assignment, but you stuck to it and got it done. That’s great! &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="358" alt="Flowchart showing the cycle of continuous learning" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/The%20Learning%20Cycle%20%282%29.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at two examples in action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Practices in Action: What it Looks Like in the Classroom&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="150" height="124" style="vertical-align: text-bottom;" alt="Magnifying glass over the words Key Practices in Action" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/keypractices_small_gray.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class had already been introduced to the following standard, which outlines a four-step writing process, and was able to put the standard in their own words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard: Convey Ideas in Writing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine the purpose for communicating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organize and present information to serve the purpose, context, and audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay attention to conventions of English language usage, including grammar, spelling, and sentence structure, to minimize barriers to reader’s comprehension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek feedback and revise to enhance the effectiveness of the communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After introducing the concept, the teacher wanted students to think about applying the standard to real life writing activities, so that they could develop the independence of being able to determine success for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class had recently been discussing their concern that prisoners from their community were being sent to Texas for their incarceration, making it nearly impossible to visit them. The teacher asked who they thought should hear their concerns – who makes the decisions – and they agreed that they wanted to write to their state policymakers. The teacher asked, according to our writing standard, what would it look like to effectively “convey ideas in writing” to those policymakers? The class then discussed the standard, bullet by bullet, and how they would know (the evidence) that the standard had been applied to carry out the task well. With some help from the teacher, they arrived at the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Task: Writing to state policymakers about the decision to send prisoners to other states for their incarceration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessment Checklist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  The ideas will be clear and make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  There will be supporting arguments for our views&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  The tone will be courteous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  We will say clearly what we're asking for (not just complain)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  We will make clear that we expect a response&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  The grammar, spelling, and punctuation will be correct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  The letter format will be correct (e.g. with an introduction, body, conclusion)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____  We will be able to explain why draft #2 is better than draft #1 (what we changed and why)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="400" height="267" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="Photo of adult students in class, completing a writing lesson" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/18125722_m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class used the checklist to guide their writing and then peer review of their drafts. While this was helpful reinforcement, the most powerful learning came from the earlier discussion of successful performance, because it was through this discussion that students connected the generic standard to what it looks like to apply the standard in real life to do real things. The class continued to develop assessment checklists for other tasks, each time honing their understanding that we adapt our use of skills to each new situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key Practices in Action: What it Looks Like in the Classroom&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="150" height="128" style="float: left;" alt="Magnifying glass over the words Key Practices in Action" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/keypractices_small.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Class Journal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Class Journal is a text I created to motivate interest in reading and provide continuity between classes. After each class, I wrote up a brief summary of what had happened that day (mentioning several students) and used it as a reading text in the next session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Class Journal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last week, two new students joined our class – Rosa and Zoila. They are both from Guatemala. They each have five children (like Maria and Concha) and they have grandchildren.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zoila is looking for a studio apartment. Carlos just moved again (the third time in two months) and now he lives on Beacon Street.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Wednesday, we read a story about Rose Sullivan. She is a divorced mother with two daughters. She was married for nine years, but she was unhappy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We talked about divorce. Zoila said that people say bad things about divorced women in her country. In the U.S., divorce is more common and accepted. But many women with children stay married because they depend on their spouses economically. This is a big problem for mothers in the U.S.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;During the first 20 minutes of each class, the group would hear the text read aloud, read it silently to mark new vocabulary and make reader notes, selected students would read aloud and tell what they understood, and all would share their responses for discussion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Class Journal created a rich opportunity to assess my advanced beginner ESOL students because it gave me a continuous flow of information about their reading abilities. But in order to capture and use that information, I needed a tool that would be easy to use, provide an objective set of criteria, be understandable (with explanation) to the students, and offer a picture of how students were progressing on the basic reading and language skills we were working on that cycle.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span size="2" style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I used my assessment tool to gather information about each student, focusing on just a couple of students each class period. I used the forms during student conference to discuss progress and provide specific feedback, and also to remind myself about which students needed additional practice in the various aspects of reading.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span size="2" style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span size="2" style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the tool that I developed for that purpose. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span size="2" style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="500" height="400" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="Screen capture of a Journal Assessment Tool" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Journal%20Assessment_cropped.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on formative assessment, explore the following resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/sites/default/files/9_TEAL_Formative_Assess.pdf"&gt;TEAL Formative Assessment Fact Sheet &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New England Literacy Resource Center’s &lt;a href="http://nelrc.org/resources/fast/"&gt;Formative Assessment of Standards&lt;/a&gt; examples with guiding questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINCS’ self-paced online course, &lt;a href="https://auth.lincs.ed.gov/idp/Authn/UserPassword"&gt;Formative Assessment to Inform Quality Adult ESL Instruction&lt;/a&gt;, in the LINCS Learning Portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" color="#693300" size="2" face="Verdana"&gt;Return to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYID*7388@$"&gt;Six key practices to promote deeper learning&lt;/a&gt; to review another key practice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: verdana; font-size: small;" color="#693300" size="2" face="Verdana"&gt;If you have finished reviewing all of the practices continue to &lt;a href="$@BOOKVIEWBYID*7389@$"&gt;Contextualized Learning and Integrated Learning Objects.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr width="33%" size="1" align="left" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn1" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref1"&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;i&gt;Education for Life and Work: Guide for Practitioners&lt;/i&gt;. Pg. 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn2" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref2"&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Ibid. Pg. 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn3" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref3"&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Vander Ark, T. and Schneider, C. (2013). Deeper Learning: For Every Student Every Day, Getting Smart, &lt;a href="http://cdno.gettingsmart.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/DLForEveryStudent_FINAL.pdf"&gt;http://cdno.gettingsmart.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/DLForEveryStudent_FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn4" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref4"&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;TEAL Math Guide Pgs. 6-7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn5" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref5"&gt;[28]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Lesgold, M. &amp;amp; Welch-Ross, M. (Eds.). Improving Adult Literacy Instruction: Options for Practice and Research. National Academies of Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ftn6"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a name="_ftn6" title="" href="file:///Y:/Shared/Client%20and%20Project%20Files/Department%20of%20Education/Kratos/Kratos%20001%20-LINCS/Task%203%20-%20EBPD%20Resources/3.2c_Allisons%20files/Del%203.2c%20WPA%20Storyboard_dev_updates.docx#_ftnref6"&gt;[29]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Andy Nash presentation to Pennsylvania ABLE case managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1506711436</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>